<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<preface version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <title>Preface</title>
  <section>
    <title>Why This Book?</title>
    <para>
      One of the biggest problems in many open source projects is the lack of proper documentation.
      This is a shame because there is not point in implementing a thousand features if no one knows about them.
      The Gallio development team was very aware of this issue, so documentation was given a high priority from
      the beginning of the project. The API reference documentation, which is automatically generated from
      the source code, was the first sign of this concern, but the team knew users need more: they need
      a guide to show them how to use the multiple features, the runners and so on under different scenarios.
      So the idea of writing a book was there from the beginning, in our wishlist, but we knew it was a big
      task so it was posponed.
    </para>
    <para>
      Around February in 2008, the topic arised again in a conversation between Jeff Brown, Gallio's lead and
      main developer, and I. The project
      was approaching a new alpha release and a beta version was not too far away either, so there was a lot
      to write about. I decided I'd go ahead and write the book myself, even though I felt (and still feel) I
      was not the best person to do it, hoping that the rest of the team and the community would help me to
      fill the gaps in my English and my time.
    </para>
    <para>
      I'm glad to see we are publishing the first draft of the book. I sincerely hope it'll help you to
      leverage the full power of this exciting platform and all the tools that are been built around it.
      Happy testing!
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Who is This Book For?</title>
    <para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Developers.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Testers.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            People wanting to extend Gallio.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </para>
  </section>
</preface>